bluetrackmedia.com 2012-12-17

# Blue Track Media : THE Incentive Advertising Agency with Innovative Proprietary Technology

**Blue Track Media, LLC, Privacy Policy**

Last updated: December 7, 2010.

Blue Track Media outlines important information in this Privacy Policy regarding the use and disclosure of information collected via www.bluetrackmedia.com.  
Blue Track Media provides this Privacy Policy to help users make an informed decision as to whether to use or continue using this website. Blue Track Media is not responsible for the information collection or privacy practices of third web sites or applications.

This Privacy Policy applies to Blue Track Media's collection, use, storage and disclosure of information by Blue Track Media on its (a) websites, including all its divisions, subsidiaries and related companies (collectively, the Website), (b) on various third party websites, and (c) to Blue Track Media's other information collection, including the purchase of customer lists from third parties.

Note: Blue Track Media has the right to change this privacy policy at anytime. Â It is the user's responsibility to check back regularly for updates.Â  Continued use of the website after this Policy has been updated constitutes acceptance of the updated Policy. If you do not agree to this privacy policy, please contact us to terminate your account immediately.

**Information collected from Third Parties.**  
Blue Track Media collects information from individuals when an individual provides information to a Third Party and Blue Track Media subsequently purchases, licenses, or otherwise acquires the information from the Third Party (the Seller). Such purchased information may include, but is not limited to, an individual's name, email address, street address, zip code, telephone numbers (including cell phone numbers and carriers), SMS messaging details (e.g. date, time and content of the SMS message), birth date, gender, salary range, education and marital status, occupation, industry of employment, personal and online interests, and such other information as the individual may have provided to the Seller (together, Third Party List Information). When acquiring Third Party List Information, Blue Track Media seeks assurances from the Seller that the Seller has a right to transfer the Third Party List Information to Blue Track Media and that the Seller has a right to provide offers from advertisers to the individuals whose personal information is included on the Seller's list.

**Information collected from Surveys.**  
Blue Track Media collects information from individuals by various methods, including, but not limited to, when an individual voluntarily completes an Blue Track Media survey, order form, or a registration page either online or offline, or by means of online or offline surveys, order forms, or registration pages operated by third parties (collectively, a Survey). (As used herein, online means using the Internet, including the Website, and related technologies, and offline means by methods other than online, including in person, in the postal mail, using telephones and cell phones, and other similar means.) In the Surveys, Blue Track Media or a third party (a Third Party) may ask an individual to provide various information to Blue Track Media, which may include his or her name, email address, street address, zip code, telephone numbers (including cell phone numbers and carriers), SMS messaging details (e.g. date, time and content of the SMS message), birth date, gender, salary range, education and marital status, occupation, social security number, employment information, personal and online interests, and such other information as may be requested from time to time (together, Survey Information). Blue Track Media may also collect information concerning an individual from another source and use that information in combination with information provided from this Web Site. Completing the Surveys is completely voluntary, and individuals are under no obligation to provide Survey Information to Blue Track Media or Third Party, but an individual may receive incentives from Blue Track Media or a Third Party in exchange for providing Survey Information to Blue Track Media.

**Other information collected.**  
Other occasions when Blue Track Media obtains information from individuals include: (a) when an individual is making a claim for a prize or seeking to redeem an incentive offered by Blue Track Media or by a Third Party,  
(b) when an individual requests assistance through Blue Track Media's customer service department,   
(c) when an individual voluntarily subscribes to a Blue Track Media service or newsletter (together, Other Information).

**Cookies.**  
A cookie is a small amount of data stored on the hard drive of the individual's computer that allows Blue Track Media to identify the individual with his or her corresponding data that resides in Blue Track Media's database. You may read more about cookies at http://cookiecentral.com . Individuals who use the Website need to accept cookies in order to use all of the features and functionality of the Website.

**Web Beacons.**  
A web beacon generally a transparent graphic image (usually a very small pixel) that is placed on a website or in an email which is used to monitor behavior of a user visiting a website or email and store their information. This allows Blue Track Media to track certain web sites an individual visits online. Web beacons are used to determine products or services an individual may be interested in, and to track online behavioral habits for marketing purposes.

**IP Address.**  
An IP Address is a form of identification and logical address of devices using Internet Protocol. Blue Track Media uses IP Addresses to track and store information in Blue Track Media's database.

**Outside Information.**  
Blue Track Media may receive information about individuals from Third Parties or from other sources of information outside of Blue Track Media including information located in public databases (Outside Information).

**Individual Information.**  
As used herein, Individual Information means Survey Information, Third Party List Information, Other Information, Technology Information, and Outside Information, and any other information Blue Track Media gathers or receives about individuals such as usage data, file transfer and viewing data.

**Children's Online Privacy Protection Act.**  
Blue Track Media will never knowingly collect any personal information about children under the age of 13. If Blue Track Media obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database. Because it does not collect such information, Blue Track Media has no such information to use or to disclose to Third Parties. Blue Track Media has designed this policy in order to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).

**Credit Card Information.**  
Blue Track Media may in certain cases collect credit card numbers and related information, such as the expiration date of the card (Credit Card Information) when an individual places an order from Blue Track Media. When the Credit Card Information is submitted to Blue Track Media, such information is encrypted and is protected with SSL encryption software. Blue Track Media will use the Credit Card Information for purposes of processing and completing the purchase transaction, and the Credit Card Information will be disclosed to Third Parties only as necessary to complete the purchase transaction. Any Credit Card information disclosed to Third Parties is not submitted to Blue Track Media and Blue Track Media does not have any control over such type of information.

**Discretion to Use Information.**  
Blue Track Media may use any information for any legal purpose in the company's sole discretion.

**1\. Email.**  
Blue Track Media uses Individual Information to provide promotional offers by email to individuals. Blue Track Media may maintain separate email lists for different purposes. If email recipients wish to end their email subscription from a particular list, they need to follow the instructions at the end of each email message to unsubscribe from the particular list. To unsubscribe from all Blue Track Media's email lists, a person must send an email to support@bluetrackmedia.com or sign into their account and make changes from there. Blue Track Media only sends email to individuals who have agreed on the Website to receive email from Blue Track Media or to individuals who have agreed on Third Party websites to receive email from Third Parties such as Blue Track Media. Blue Track Media does not send unsolicited email messages. As a result, statutes requiring certain formatting for unsolicited email are not applicable to Blue Track Media's email messages.

**2\. Individual Information.**  
Blue Track Media stores the Individual Information in a database on Blue Track Media computers and our hosting servers. Our computers have security measures (such as a firewall) in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under Blue Track Media's control. Although we have these security measures, Blue Track Media cannot guarantee that its security measures will prevent Blue Track Media computers from being illegally accessed, and the Individual Information on them stolen or altered. By signing up you have agreed to understand that Blue Track Media will not be liable for any information that has been hacked from our computers or servers.

**Sell to Third Parties.**  
Blue Track Media holds the right to sell or transfer any type of information (individual, summary, etc) to third parties for any reason necessary.  
**Deleting and Updating Your Information.**  
If you would like to delete or update the personally identifiable information that we have collected from you (name, address, etc.), simply send your request to Blue Track Media, LLC at support@bluetrackmedia.com.   
We will process your request, where possible and subject to the terms and conditions contained herein, within a reasonable period of time after receipt. To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to help verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.  
**Legal Process.**  
Blue Track Media may disclose Individual Information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, and other legal processes.

**Fraud/Scams.**  
It is Blue Track Media's right to close or dismiss any clients or accounts without pay if Blue Track Media has a suspicion of fraudulent activity or a suspicion of scam. As a publisher or advertiser it is your duty to limit the fraudulent activity that appears on your account. Blue Track Media holds the right to share any views on your account with other beneficiaries.

**Advertiser cookies and web beacons.**  
Blue Track Media does not control Advertisers' use of such technology and Blue Track Media has no responsibility for the use of such technology to gather information about individuals.

**Links.**  
The Website and email messages sometimes contain hypertext links to the web sites of Third Parties. Blue Track Media is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other web sites. Linked web sites may contain links to web sites maintained by Third Parties. Such links are provided for your convenience and reference only. Blue Track Media does not operate or control in any respect any information, software, products or services available on such Third Party web sites. The inclusion of a link to a web site does not imply any endorsement of the services or the site, its contents, or its sponsoring organization.

**International person(s).**  
Anyone using the Website outside of the United States acknowledges that personal information will be collected and stored by Blue Track Media in the United States. By using the Website, you consent to the transfer of information to and/or storage of information outside of your country and in the United States.

**Contact.**  
If you have any questions or comments on this privacy policy, please feel free to contact us at [support@bluetrackmedia.com](mailto:support@bluetrackmedia.com). You may also write to us at:  **[insert mailing address]**.
